Finding Aid for Ann Arbor Women Painters records, 1951-2001
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Ann Arbor Women Painters records
1951-2001
Ann Arbor Women Painters.
8554 Bp 2
Formerly known as the Women Painters' Group and affiliated, 1951-1960, with the Ann Arbor Art Association and the Women's City Club. In 2002, the name of the organization was changed to Ann Arbor Women Artists. Historian's books containing yearbooks, newspaper clippings, membership lists, officer reports, and exhibition material.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
6 linear feet
The records were donated by the organization (donor no. 6375 ) and first came to the library in 1979.
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The record group is open to research.
AAWA was founded in 1951 as a volunteer organization and study group, called Ann Arbor Women Painters. The organizers of this group were Sarah Bull, Elsie Bailey and Doris Porter Mclean.
In 2002 the name was changed to Ann Arbor Women Artists to more accurately portray its members - artists working in a variety of media and producing vastly different types of art.
The purpose of the AAWA is to stimulate creative expression and sharing among its members in order to continually raise the quality of the art produced. Run as a volunteer organization, members exhibit their work in several different shows and exhibition spaces throughout the year. The organization also offers workshops and monthly events, including presentations by artists and others in the art field who speak on a wide variety of topics.
The records of the organization include clippings, programs, directories of members, minutes of meetings and annual reports, records of the historian and of the exhibition committee.
Subjects:
Art--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Artists--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Arts--Michigan--Ann Arbor--Societies, etc.; Women--Michigan--Ann Arbor--Societies and clubs.; Ann Arbor Art Association.; Ann Arbor Women Painters.
- Scrapbook-binders
  - 1952-1964 (Box 1)
    (binder contains clippings, programs, directory)
  - 1964-1973 (Box 1)
  - 1973-1981 (Box 1)
  - 1981-1986 (Box 2)
  - 1987-1991 (Box 2)
    (binder contains clippings, programs, photographs)
- Business Records
  (minutes and annual reports)
  - 1951-1966 (Box 3)
  - 1966-1981 (Box 3)
  - 1981-1986 (Box 3)
  - 1986-1993 (Box 3)
    (continued in Historian's books)
- Historian's Records
  - 1986-1990 (Box 4)
    (binder contains clippings, programs, directories, and business records)
  - 1990-1994 (Box 4)
  - 1994-1997 (Box 4)
    (contains programs, newsletters, minutes, treasurer's reports, etc.)
  - 1997-1999 (Box 4)
- Exhibition Committee
  - 1979-1989 (Box 5)
  - 1989-1996 (Box 5)
  - 1996-1997 (Box 5)
  - 1997-1998 (Box 5)
- Other Records
  - Newsletters, 1990-2000 (Box 6)
  - Directories, 1961-2001 (Box 6)
  - Treasurer's book, 1989-1992 (Box 6)
  - Ledger and dues book, 1951-1962 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous directories, clippings and informational materials, 1950s (Box 6)
  - Mary Bachman (?) (nominating committee chair, newsletter editor) record book, 1983-1993 (Box 6)
    (contains programs, newsletters, etc.)